yeah uh this controller like move up and
down the elevator so oh my gosh dude
they talk about like impact right like
exactly talk about like oh yeah you know
your database is going to see like a you
know performance deficit and they're
like your elevator will literally drop
like
[Music]
[Applause]
so we've all been on those pentests
before right where we're just banging
our head into the external attack
surface of a company for what feels like
an eternity and then when you finally
get inside the network it's like open
freaking season there are accessible
shares everywhere CVS are popping left
and right there's seemingly no controls
at all on what ports can or cannot be
accessed too many companies are
neglecting your internal network
security and that's why threat Locker
came up with this product Network
control which makes it super easy to
control what kind of ports are Exposed
on a given host whether that be a user
machine or a server the thing I like the
most about Network control is that it
understands far more than just the IP
layer you can allocate specific controls
to keywords or tags and then use those
to manage access from different machines
regardless of whether they change IPS or
not so if you're looking to sh up your
internal Network make sure you check out
Network control by threat Locker all
right let's go back to the
show all right dude yeah let's go I am
looking at this Doc and we have a banger
today dude there's so much good content
in here um so I'm super excited shiron
welcome to the podcast man thank you
very much yeah I'm really happy to be
here today dude and uh right before the
episode we were we were just you know
talking about our hacker swag in the
background uh for those of you following
on YouTube and we got the pone to own
trophy right behind you there yeah yeah
we have uh we have it right here oh my
God dude all right that's on my list
dude that is on my list I got to get one
of those I got a got a hacker one mvh I
got a Google mvh and then I gotta get I
gotta get one of those pone trophies man
that that yeah you'll get it I'm sure
you'll get it one day well dude we'll
we'll definitely talk a little bit more
about that but um I just so let me let
me let me give a little context here
okay so um one of the problems that I
see with the bug Bounty world right now
is that there's a decent amount of
segmentation right um there's there's
like the hacker one bug crowd Squad and
then there's like the Ponto own Squad
and then there's a bunch of other little
sub communities like Google has their
own researcher base meta has their own
researcher base that sort of thing um
and as I've been you know sort of living
in the hacker one bug crowd Integrity
space for a long time I I I started
getting a little bit interested in some
of these other uh other you know bug
vounty niches like pone to own and stuff
and so I we did an episode with sin
anology which was amazing um and and uh
and then at this live hacking event this
hacker one live hacking event I see this
random guy that that just just comes
comes onto the stage you know does this
amazing showand tell extremely
technically dense um amazing performance
and that is user and that started the
Deep dive that started the research and
then I I I say who's who's this who's
the Chiron guy and then I I I start I
start looking into it I start finding
all your writeups and stuff and holy
crap dude like what a port folio um so I
guess man where do we even start I guess
can you give me a little bit of
background for um for how you got to
this point as a researcher where you're
competing in hacker one live hacking
events and taking away words competing
in pone to own and then somehow solving
fishing in Israel on the weekends like
give me a little cont I'm embarrassed
I'm blushed uh thanks man uh yeah you
know um uh I started pretty early I mean
today there are a lot of uh 8-year-old
kids that are building iOS applications
but yeah uh my my journey started
actually with the first iPhone uh so I
got this uh present um my mom didn't
want that uh my my dad to buy uh the
first iPhone because she told him it's
uh it's too luxury um but uh he decided
to to buy uh buy me the first iPhone I
really remember this it was the uh 2010
2011 I think um maybe earlier um and I
got the iPhone and I started to develop
iOS applications for the the first
iPhone I I I remember the day that the
App Store was born and uh I submitted my
app I was very anxious and I got got
submitted so this is I was around uh the
age of 16 but and I submitted the first
stop and I started to do some money out
of iOS applications in W very early days
uh uh like the the first app that I had
was was a reminder application was
completely crap but the thing is I was
intrigued uh to develop I I was uh
incentivized and I got motivated to to
learn computers so uh I I owe this to to
my father to be honest that's amazing
you know so when when you get started
early like that I think it's a different
it's a different world you know uh it's
something that becomes a part of you
really really core um on early in the
process um but yeah so you start in the
in the iOS um development I get the iOS
world and then and then where do we go
from there how do we turn into the
hacker that we are today so I I started
as iOS Developer I I I started I had
Hackintosh so I I did not have enough
money to buy uh a Mac computer so I I
did a lot of Google to understand how do
I create Hackintosh VM uh it was a thing
but back then so uh because I had no
money I had to do some hacking in order
to create like a virtual Mech OSX uh
which is hacking doosh uh and this is
how I started to develop applications uh
um um learn some computer stuff uh I I
needed to uh gain some knowledge in
order to do uh certain stuff so for
example uh I had to use some kind of a
database I did not know what a database
is I just knew I need to store some
information
so so I think my hacking knowledge uh
was built layer by layer by um myself
needed to do something right uh so I
started as I developer and then I
started to do some uh website
development and and then uh I I did some
kind of hacking I would say you know I I
tried to do uh web hacking and try to
understand what is a JavaScript and
client side and their server side okay
so you did start in the web World a
little bit right right then just just a
little bit yeah just a little bit all
right that's that's one of the things
that I'm like you know as a web as
primarily a web guy I look at a lot of
these pwn to own stuff and I'm like wow
this is like so much time and effort put
into these exploits in these in this
research right um and so it's cool to
see you know especially if somebody
started in in the web Arena and then
shifted into that that more um you know
low-level exploitation uh you know
afterwards because that that shows you
know the continued commitment to depth
depth depth um yeah I I think it I think
one of the one of the things that I've
is a Common Thread that I've seen across
a lot of hackers though is that sort of
like not really hacking but sort of
hacky path right where it's like oh you
know I had to build this whole like you
know ecosystem to do the thing that I
wanted to do and it wasn't really like
hacking but it was hacky you know um I I
think that's I think that's pretty
pretty consistent across the board and I
think it sets you up for the right kind
of mentality going into hacking long
term yeah I agree I agree I think that
um hackers I would say uh you know folks
that uh did not start from a educational
background you know from University or
something like that they started from a
place where they wanted to build
something um and then uh acquired the
knowledge to do that layer by by layer
this is the hacker mentality that you're
talking about totally agree yep uh so
yeah I did some uh applications and then
a little bit uh uh uh web especially
because I needed to to build the back
end for my applications so that's where
I started with u mostly PHP um um
classic
classic uh and and then a little bit of
python uh but but then I started uh uh I
I started to be exposed to C to the CTF
world and then I started to do ctfs uh
and this is where I really started uh
kind of um my my actual uh gaining
knowledge into binary exploitation and
um actually uh hacking competitions so I
did a lot of ctfs I'm still doing when I
have time and when my wife is not metad
at me because yeah I'm like what do you
mean when you have time you're like
doing all this iot research you're doing
web hacking stuff you're do oh my gosh
dude that's crazy do I mean do you
remember how you first got that exposure
to ctfs though I'm wondering if that was
like through University or something you
just found online or what I I think that
one of my friends told me hey there is
this uh Google hacking competition I
think it was Google I'm not I'm not sure
uh and I was uh wow it sound sounds cool
I really wanted to be in hacker uh and
then I I signed up for the CDF and I did
not understand nothing I mean I I did
not understand what is a binary
exploitation what is stock buffer
overflow I mean I knew nothing and and
this is a great great starting point for
someone who is very curious uh to to see
a lot of different terminology and and
cool stuff that they want to do but they
don't understand or they do not know it
and this is a great uh starting point to
start learning about this stuff
absolutely so that's that's my kind of
my journey I I saw something that I
really uh wanted to get experience with
and and understand U and I knew nothing
and so I started a bit by bit you know
all the uh starting uh ctfs and um uh
little little competitions this is uh a
great place to start well you you learn
the things to Google too right like
you're like oh I didn't even know what
Bing exploitation was or like what a
stack Overflow was or whatever right and
and and so you know then you you come
out of that CTF and you're like okay now
I know I gotta go home and I got to
figure that out you know um exact and
and I think that's how we grow um no
that that that's a great a great story
and I think um it's it's clear you know
the kind of um academic motivation or uh
intellectual motivation that a lot of
the hackers bring to the table where
it's like oh I don't understand this
thing I'm not going to give up on that
I'm gonna just keep on you know pounding
it until I freaking understand that
because I am gonna become a hacker you
know uh yeah I love that man okay so so
fast forwarding a little bit we've got
you know we've got a black badge where
sans's you know re Institute researcher
of the Year we're winning live hacking
events left and right um yeah dude it
it's it's amazing so tell me a little
bit about about the day job now and uh
how you how you participate in bug
bounties currently yeah so fast word
today uh I'm managing the the research
Department uh uh at a company in a
company called Clarity uh so um clarity
as a company uh develops IDs for scatter
networks uh this means we have a really
good understanding and kind of um
isoteric protocols uh that are very
popular among scan n Works uh so I
started uh in Clarity uh as a protocol
um analyst you can call it I guess dude
what a freaking cool name protocol
analyst that's amazing yeah so I I mean
my my journey in this company started
where where I we needed to add more
support in in in more protocols that are
not uh open right so they're they're
closed uh uh closed systems and somehow
we needed to add support into our
product to understand how these
protocols work oh you know there there
was like some product I I I I saw this
from one of your talks but there's like
some product right where or or some um
protocol where you know it's connecting
to all of these different SK devices
right and it and it's conglom you know
pulling all this data in together and I
think one of the major problems with
this you know sort of ska industry is
that there are a bunch of propriety
protocols and nothing talks to each
other right the main problem okay so so
a company like Clarity uh and its
competitors were born because of this uh
spaghetti of protocols and devices that
nobody could keep follow because in the
past scan networks were air gaed nobody
could talk to them so there was not a
not not a not a security problem because
nobody could reach out to these uh
environments but because of convergence
it and OT kind of converion now you can
access your OT devices from the internet
from yeah that's scary uh so they asset
owners started uh uh needed a solution
to understand what do they have in their
Network and how can they protect so
that's kind of how or why Clarity was
worn but um fast forward to my role I
needed to add support in different
protocols that uh nobody knew how they
work and we only had the equipment in
our lab uh so we have a cool lab in t
Aviv uh where we uh plug we buy and plug
in all the devices and we need to
research uh how these devices work and
how the protocol works so dude I just I
totally like geeking out right now about
how amazing that job is like what a what
a breeding ground for a hacker right
like you know constantly reverse
engineering protocols you know and it's
like oh my gosh that's amazing exactly
so I mean this is where my curiosity
reached its pick because uh I needed to
understand how a blackbox device that is
managing I don't know let's say uh water
utilities or or gas P pipelines which is
super cool how these devices controllers
work and how I can uh operate these
devices with these isoteric protocols
and I need to understand the protocols
really good so I did a lot of bunch of
uh reverse engineering into FW and
embedded devices and protocol analysis
and blind protocol analysis where you
have like this streams of of bits and
bytes and you need to understand okay
this is the header this is the command
uh so that's that's really cool so I
started uh you know really from the
handson to understand how this protocol
works and you know while doing reverse
and journeying into the main functions
of FW I started to to see some uh you
know buffer overflows potentials so uh I
kind of you know I I created like a
small PLC python script that uh
overflows the stack and suddenly the
device crashed and we're talking about
controllers that actually uh you know uh
transform or gener responsible for
generation of electricity I mean that's
super scary uh this controller like move
up and down the elevator so oh my gosh
dude they talk about like impact right
like exact talk about like oh yeah you
know your database is going to see like
a you know uh performance deficit and
they're like your elevator will
literally drop
yeah I mean I can shut down and and I
did this before I can shut down like
entire building so modern cities uh and
modern um uh buildings have these uh
tons of BMS system building machine uh
building management systems so the HVAC
is uh fully controlled all the doors are
fully uh remotely uh controlled um all
the gas and pipelines and the the water
everything is is is managed by you know
ethernet protocols and uh I had the
chance uh the opportunities uh to shut
down an entire building nobody can can
go up or down the elevator nobody can
exit the doors my god dude that's that's
crazy have you ever seen the movie
National Treasure with Nicholas Cage
okay so this is like you this is like so
when I was a kid I was like oh man like
I see this guy Riley you know or
whatever the guy the hacker in that
movie right that like helps the dude
steal the the Constitution or whatever
and and I was like that's the guy that I
want to be you know he's like he's like
all right I'm in I'm in the system I'm
like locking the doors that's exactly
what you're surprised and you'd be
surprised uh you know the only thing
that prevents you from doing that is
getting access to these uh platforms
which is uh very expensive but since I
work in this company that uh you know
our Forte is those systems I get access
to these type of systems and there are
tons of bugs over there tons of bugs
from web bugs to Binary exploitation
bugs to uh you know there there are ton
of tons of bugs that are just waiting
for researchers to uh to find because
nobody can access this equipment because
it's expensive so yeah I have to say
like normally when I think about my job
you know I'm like I don't have a lot of
job Envy like I'm like man you know
professional live hacking event
participant self-employed doing this
podcast is exactly what I want to be
doing that is really cool like that that
actually gives me a little bit of job
Envy right there where you just got like
this whole playground of of toys you
know that that are used to control real
buildings and real like physical systems
that you get to hack um yeah yeah I mean
it's cool it's cool I've been doing this
for a long time so yeah maybe we'll get
back to the story so I started as a as a
protocol analyst I did a lot of reverse
engineering into FW to understand how
this protocol works and uh you know I
added uh visibility into a product that
means uh okay we see
this stream stream of bites this
actually means move the elevator one
level up right so you can take it to uh
BMS building management system so you
can take it to oil and gas you know like
open the valve close the valve so every
physical command has its equivalent in
the network protocol and this is what I
needed to understand um so it was very
cool I I I learned a lot of uh from it
um most of my U um embedded knowledge is
from uh this type of work but as I said
with time I started to understand okay
this is the main switch of all the
commands right so if it's a um uh 0x uh
ZF this means this is a mve the elevator
app but then I see okay if if there is
uh more data in the packet than the the
buffer is allocated you you can achieve
buffer overflow and then take control
over some kind of uh uh uh flow the code
flow like uh the instruction pointer of
the device and then you can achieve
remote code execution so I started to to
notice a lot of this because again no
researcher ever looked at these devices
these type of bugs are not complicated
exactly untouched like a um a blue ocean
uh Virgin Territory yeah so uh so I just
started to report these bugs to Simmons
to Rockwell to Schneider to AB to all
the all the great names that uh actually
are the majority of uh um the critical
infrastructure vendors uh of the modern
times um and they started to fix it you
know so um uh with time I I reached to
like 30 CVS 50 CVS wow and and again
just because I had the opportunity uh to
work on this uh to uh in this uh
unfamiliar territory that nobody looked
before and so I opened the vulnerability
research team with Clarity with the main
focus of okay here's the lab go over all
the devices find all the bugs you can
report it to the vendors and work with
them to to issue patches because
eventually our customers are are using
these products and we want our customers
to be secure yeah so at the end of the
day you know okay so it went it went
from you originally reverse engineering
these protocols to integrate it into the
product to now we're running the the
research team the security team because
our customers are using these products
and they they need to be secured wow
exactly dude that's that is amaz I got I
got goosebumps a little bit man that's
that's amazing so that's that is super
cool um that's that's like the
transition I I was fortunate enough uh
uh to experience um and and now uh you
know the vulnerability research grew and
grew and grew and now I'm managing the
department of um um research we call
ourselves that team 82 this is like our
our external brand name of of the
research team we do a lot of uh um OT
hacking which is a skyum I can deep dive
into OT if You' like and we also do iot
because uh we grew in grew with time so
now we do more devices like medical
devices for example we're we're writing
exploits to hack a patient monitor you
know to change the heart bit dud no no
that's crazy I I saw one of your demos
you know uh live I think on a stage with
you're hacking a medical device that was
like literally connected to your arm um
yeah yeah that's that's cool I mean
again it's not complicated um and I and
I think the the the fact that it's not
very complicated um uh pushed me into
bug b is yeah so that's that's what I
wanted to ask as well and I you know
okay I've said my I fan boyed enough a
little bit now I'll try not to give you
too big of a head you know but that is
really cool um man uh but yeah let's
let's talk about the nuts and bolts of
it right so you know you're in this
environment you keep on saying okay
these is a a lot of times these you know
SK systems are untouched right they're
they're not really vetted for security
problems right um and so obviously
that's the opposite of what you
experience whenever you work on like a
like a
um a bug Bounty program that's that's
hardened you know um so what brought you
into the bug Bounty world and how has
that been going from something that's
very lowlevel and very blackbox to
something that is uh definitely very
hardened yeah yeah it's a it's a good
question so I mean with time uh that you
exploit um a lot of uh different uh
devices you you start to understand the
pattern like how the device and the fer
and the logic is built like what what
crossed through the developers mind when
they built the product and uh what kind
of checks they're they're doing and what
kind of uh checks they're probably
missing so I think if you take uh this
experience uh from kind of a gray box
testing you know black black box white
box you don't have the full code but you
can do some reverse engineering of the
firware you start to understand the
pattern that you're looking for in other
platforms um and and so I think the
transition uh is kind of makes sense
when you you kind of understand or at
least think that you understand what
types of checks uh are usually
overlooked and you start from these
points that you uh try to poke uh at
different areas of of um um of the
platform or or the logic uh to try to do
it blackbox wise yeah that that makes
sense and so then you know when you're
moving into something like pwn to own
you know are are you
seeing what what is the difficulty level
differential there like like because
you're you said before a lot of these
are untouched and then you go into
something like pwn to own where there's
a lot of researchers hacking on the same
stuff you know that difficulty level
goes up a lot I'd
imagine so I I agree with you so what
happened is we did in in our team uh we
did a lot of uh um you know exploitation
of scatter devices and a little bit of
iot devices and then we we saw uh pone
to own so this uh this was a great
opportunity for us uh to start trying
like the real world stuff like okay
right here in our lab we have these
devices that probably nobody touched but
let's let's try to take a real challenge
into devices that targets that zdi uh
zero the initiative are specifically
targeting because they're pop because
everybody are looking at them right uh
and and we had a great success so Pon
let's talk just a little bit about P so
p uh has this uh uh three or four themes
of competitions uh the first one is the
classic one where they have the
operating system and browsers uh
competition uh which we're not competing
yet yeah that's super intense uh uh and
then they have the iot
competition uh the IC competition which
they stopped uh doing and they also now
started with the automotive competition
so we we mainly focused on on the other
three so the automotive iot and the IC
or OT um uh by the way just for
terminology OT operational technology IC
industrial Control Systems uh so we're
we're talking about yeah I I didn't know
Ot Ot that that's interesting okay yeah
yeah operational technology this is like
it's like it but with operational with
something physical sure uh uh so we're
talking about scatter like uh devices
that have some um uh kind of interface
with physical interface with the world
yeah okay that makes sense so we focused
mostly on the IC and iot and we had a
great success um and if we're getting
back to your question like how difficult
it is uh so yeah it's it's much very
difficult the attack surface is very
limited and many eyes uh uh review it a
lot of times uh but still we had we had
uh some success which was uh great and
we actually did a five times uh of
different pone tones wow man that's
that's so fun that's so fun yeah it is
it is it is a lot of fun uh so showing
your exploit live is is really cool dude
that's got to be really nerve-wracking
too if it's like this one moment of like
does the exploit work does the exploit
not work everything comes down into one
oh my gosh dude okay so so then let's um
let's kind of talk about pwn to own
versus the the hacker one live hacking
events and then we rewind a little bit
into some of your your bug Bounty
experience before that so um you know
you said at these pone to own
competitions zdi is selecting these
these targets that are specifically used
because they're specifically selected
because they're popular right um and
these are going to be more hardened
because more eyes have been on them uh
naturally um and and so you know there
there's more time required for these
events and that's one of the things that
I've seen between hacker 1's live
hacking events and P own's competitions
is that there's a massive time component
that difference right hacker one it's
normally you've got like two weeks to
hack these these companies or these
devices or whatever and then zdi you
know I don't even know how how far in
advance do they do it usually three
months three months wow okay and I
mean can you give me a little bit of a
timeline on how that works I mean I'm
sure it varies from product to product
but do you spend three months focusing
on one product do you do one month one
month one month or like how does that
work yeah it's it's it's a great
question so usually uh um I'm doing P
toon with my team right um so usually we
uh 3 to five okay depends on
availability um and and yeah so three
months ahead of time phone to own or zdi
um they released the target list and uh
U let's let's say we're talking about
the iot competition so you have like the
router category and you have the um uh
Nas devices category and you have uh a
smart uh um smart cameras categor so
different categories and and you have a
bunch of uh devices with a price tag so
if you are able to exploit a IP camera
remotely specific one you get 30k for
example so what uh my myself and my team
are doing uh we're we're taking this uh
this list and we're starting to do some
asint on all the devices how easy it is
to get the finware how how many uh
previous CVS and bugs were reported uh
how many times this device uh uh was um
targeted in previous pons uh and and we
have these metrix where we uh decide on
what targets we want to focus on have
you have you actually Quantified it like
that like you've got this matrix it's
like all right it's been targeted at one
p own so that's like a you know8
multiplier or something like that yeah I
mean it's not it's not very mathematical
but but yeah we have the we have these
categories or parameters you can call so
what what's the price tag how how is it
is to get the device how is it is to
extract the fanware which is a a really
important factor to be honest yeah uh
and how many times uh was it targeted
before and how many CVS you have it so
I'm running this random I love that that
it's actually like you have metrics for
this and and you're making a choice
based off of a procedure yeah we must
have this because you have like uh 20 or
30 targets and and you have to be very
very specific because you can spend like
a year on a target for example uh the
guys that are doing the Tesla components
ecus uh are spending like a year on on
on these exploits and we want to be very
focused because we have three months and
we want to get as much as devices as we
can and usually uh we're able to get
like uh five or six devices in this uh
time frame so we have to be very focused
let me ask you this
um so there's a a sort of a problem that
I run into with these Live Hack events
which is sometimes I want to win the
live hacking event and I want to come in
first right and sometimes I want to make
as much money as I can and those you
know those don't
necessarily um true you know Collide
always right like like for example on
the hacker one live hacking events um
you when it's multi-target to get the
mvh you kind of have to hack both
targets um for for but if you want to
make the most money in my experience
it's best to pick one target go super
deep destroy it you know like like find
a bunch of criticals and that sort of
thing right so when you're going into
Theon to own competitions like what is
your your goal or what is your team's
goal typically for these things yeah so
typically it we are taking into
consideration the amount of money and
points because P toon are separating the
points and the money and the winner uh
is the one with the most points and not
money uh so that's exactly the the kind
of the uh questions uh that the the
competitors are pondering like we want
more points or more money um so we
usually tend uh um tend to towards the
the points like we want to get higher on
the table rather than than money uh but
I guess it changes um um it fluctuates
between competitions and and is this is
this something you're doing as a part of
Team 82 or like as a part of your job or
is this something you're doing sort of
uh after hours with the team from work
um so yeah it's kind of a mix I I'd say
uh we're doing this as as t82 we're
competing as t82 right um but during
these times uh uh of the year we are
spending a lot of more time uh than
usual and uh and we also need to do our
like day-to-day job like usual job so it
it it's always uh like overtime I I'd
say like it's good are for the company
as well you know if you guys are going
out there destroying those those um
those targets so then I guess I wonder
how much so the prize money then does
that go to the company or does that go
to the team so we're kind of uh
splitting it uh through the team
okay um but evenly because we're all
putting the same amount of effort into
the targets into the research sometimes
we're building custom tools for that uh
so yeah yeah I imagine you're doing a
lot of building custom tools when you
have these proprietary protocols and
like that yeah we have to we have to
because uh you know just like uh uh
let's take an example from the web
hacking you know sometimes you have like
a Target that you want to scan it across
the entire internet and you want to to
do some kind of specific logic and so
it's kind of the same with finware
sometimes you want to poke the FW you
you want to for example ask questions
about all the functions like what kind
of functions contain this specific uh
code flow that uh I might uh abuse
somehow so yeah we're we're building
like custom scripts custom tools uh to
to ask and answer these specific
questions okay so let me let me double
click into that for a second so what is
your what is your go-to language and
like some packages that you use for a
lot of this stuff so I I usually uh
exclusively use Python and Bash uh for
for scripting it's my man my man okay I
love it I love it it's the the fastest
way to uh to move forward um and i' I'd
say that uh for uh kind of um packages
for python you have uh the pone the pone
one yeah the P tools or whatever yeah
yeah pone tools uh you know for uh um
easy interaction with the targets i' say
you know sending payloads receiving
payloads uh stuff like that yeah I'll
drop that in the I'll drop that in the
notes for those people that are
interested in that um yeah no I I've
seen that and and I haven't used it
super much I've done a lot of uh I guess
most of the binary stuff that I've done
has only been uh very limited so I
haven't had the chance to use it
extensively but it seems very very
useful um it's very useful it just
contains all the all the you know go-to
functions uh you know conversion between
uh different U big Indian the Indian and
you have a hack formats and it's very
convenient to use it very easy that that
seems to be the case um so uh one of the
questions we put in the dock here was
like all right give me give me the the
Chiron um you know breakdown on what
hacker one is doing right with the life
hacking events and what they're doing
wrong versus what pontone is doing right
um yeah so so let me let let me get your
opinion on that and then we'll we'll
talk about a couple of those as well
yeah sure so uh again you know these
type of competitions are completely
different uh so in hacker one live
hacking events uh you have like two two
weeks of preparation and then the the
live event is like uh 48 hours max uh
for hacking so uh you don't have a lot
of time to go very deep uh so it's more
for me list it's more of a social event
right it's it's more of a community wise
you get to know a lot of different
people and uh maybe to do some collabs
with them so uh it's it's really great
uh to uh know a lot of people from from
the industry uh while PTO own so you
spend uh three month by yourself at home
alone right
in the dark in the
dungeon and then you go for uh one or
two days and just show your exploit and
that's it so it's it's much less of a
community event much less uh of um uh um
kind of a social event I mean you do get
to know people there but it's much less
focused on community uh but it's much
more Deep dive so we have one target
like one device or two devices and and
you you do a deep dive into that you
know all the F were by hard you know all
the functions you know all the
interfaces you know all the attack
vectors on it uh so it's much much more
uh Deep dive also uh in P to own uh uh
so zdi folks are running P to own and
they are super
technical uh they're hackers themselves
and they do a lot of uh hacking
themselves so they understand the
research uh that you provide them really
good and they will fight for you with
the vendor so this is amazing so for
examp let's say that I was able to
demonstrate a success successful
exploited P to own and for some reason
the vendor does not agree with that uh
so zdi will fight for you they will uh
shove it into the vendor and will tell
them you need to fix it no matter what
uh and this is this is great because it
it really pushes the entire industry the
entire industry uh forward because zdi
puts a lot of pressure into vendors to
uh to make things right and they fight
for their researchers and I really
appreciate that just it just warms the
heart doesn't it when you see like your
Advocate out there being like no this is
fire this is a great exploit you need to
fix it you know I'll give you a contra
for that so sometimes I'm submitting
bugs to H1 and it's like it feels to me
like a flip of a coin that it will be
I'm I'm submitting as critical and it
will be closed as informative so yeah so
when I submit bugs to zdi and Pon I know
they will get it I know they will do the
right thing and push the vendor one of
the one of the most challenging things
with hacker one and Bug Crow Integrity
is like you have to they have so much
volume that they have to this massive
triager problem to solve right and it
and the triers burn out pretty quickly
so it's hard to keep like you know high
quality triers on the team and stuff
like that so you do run into those
issues um and I will say I I haven't
experienced the ponton side and I'm sure
that would be so heartwarming to see
them fighting for your bug but um I have
had a couple experiences with hacker one
once you I think it's like maybe the top
300 researchers or something like that
on hacker one get access to this thing
called an HSM hacker success manager and
they're the person that I ping when I
run into that sort of problem right like
oh my report closed is informative hey
man this is not informative can you like
take care of that and and then you know
and and and it happens so and when it
does I'm like ah H I'm so pleased by
that that just makes me so happy and
feel so appreciated um so yeah exactly
so the problem is volume I I I I totally
agree I mean when you have a lot of
volume especially new hackers coming in
uh and and just like pushing uh bugs
without understanding uh but I think
that I I understand the HSM uh thing but
I think that hackers with more um uh
credibility to their name and and more
uh mileage they their assessment of bugs
needs to be a little bit different
that's that's my take on it I totally
agree I wish there was there I mean
obviously there's the reputation metrics
and stuff like that but that doesn't
that doesn't correlate with hackers that
are new to the hacker one platform but
very experienced hackers so there needs
to be some sort of um I guess premium
onboarding or something like that for
hackers that have experience on other
platforms or in other competitions or
something like that yeah I I had a case
I mean it's very interesting when I had
a case when or when I submitted a bug as
high I think uh and it was close by the
triager uh it was closed as informative
uh he told me uh it's not it's not not
interesting I can feel my pulse just
like that just gets you in the heart
doesn't it when they do that yeah you
know so I was new on the platform and
then I wrote like oh I'm sorry I will
not submit this type of bug anymore and
then the vendor reopened the case
assigned it as high and paid the Bounty
and I was like wow okay yeah that's
that's crazy yeah well I love your
response dude your response is like oh
okay my bad my bad you know no I'll just
take this high or critical explain and
just you know okay I guess it's not real
oh man no you got to fight you got to
fight and that's what I tell people when
they're when they go to these live
hacking events is like that's one of the
best things about being in person at the
live hacking events is like if you've
got some bug that's being um you know uh
incorrectly the severity assigned to it
yeah classified then you can just go
knock on the triage door and say like
you know hey I need to talk to somebody
from the team or from triage and I need
to explain how this bug works and you
can just sit down with them in person
and be like hey here's the exploit
clearly this is a problem you know like
it is it is it is and but again I I do
understand the volume issue I
mean yeah it's it's what it is it is um
Let me let me talk about this because
there's two main main things that that I
think I'd like to discuss about pwn to
own versus versus hacker one here that
we've got left one is that um pone to
own only does pre-o RC um and I think
that leaves a lot on the table uh what
are your what are your thoughts on that
having been in the hacker one
environment now where uh other types of
exploits are also um appreciated so
again p is very exclusive uh competition
they want uh you know they want to do
kind of uh um PC or get a [__] out right
so they want pre RC they want you to run
code on this device preferably as rout M
uh or it's not interesting I mean why
it's not interesting because this is not
part of the competition the pwn to own
like pone to own you need to own the
device right that's the competition um
while they do understand there is a lot
of attack surface and and you know while
we're targeting five devices when we're
preparing for p to own and you know we
have like five PR RCS we have like 50
different bugs that are not included in
the competition and we're submitting
that later to zdi and they accept them
they process and they make the vendor
fix them so that that's fine I mean
that's part of the competition uh but in
the competition itself they only want uh
preor because that's the the rules of
the competition hacker one uh um live
hacking events uh they they have this
range you know low medium high critical
uh because they understand that um Li
actual targets have different attack
surface and they want all of it so yeah
and and that is the case I'm wondering
if you were to build your perfect live
hacking competition what what would you
do you know would would would you given
the opportunity say Okay Pon to own
should accept uh you know something like
arbitrary account takeover where you can
just get into any device and take over
people's account or like um uh dosses
that that take down the whole the whole
service right where the device becomes
inaccessible um you know those those are
very impactful bugs and and I'm
wondering whether you think those should
be uh like like what happens to those
bugs because you know inevitably you
stumble upon them right when you're
trying to find these preo rce so I mean
you just report them to the vendor and
you don't get any money for them so you
can so if you have bugs that uh you
found uh and you did not use them
through P toon you can still submit them
to zti you can actually so zdi are
purchasing bugs that that's that's the
kind of their business model they they
pay for vulnerabilities because zdi are
owned by Trend Micro the the AV company
yeah uh or ADR now I'm not sure uh and
so zdi wants to get the new exploits the
new bugs the new vulnerabilities and
they will purchase them from researchers
and they will submit them to the vendors
and this is where they really useful in
fighting with the vendors and push them
into fixing the the security
vulnerabilities and then uh Tren micro
will develop detection so this is kind
of their business model so if you find
bugs that are not pre- ourc there you
can still use them you can still uh sell
them to ZD okay okay that's cool and and
and do they pay out all right yeah yeah
they pay they pay great I mean they
don't have uh like a predefined um
metric table bount table whatever okay
uh the Bounty table Yeah but they pay
they pay great and and they also have
tiers so you can you can move forward
with reputation and as long um uh with
more bugs that you're selling them and
more reputation you actually move
forward like just like a freaking
flyer sure yeah wow uh so we have like
uh silver bronze I forgot the tiers but
yeah uh uh and you get multipliers so
yeah they they have a great program for
that dang that sounds pretty awesome I
wasn't aware of that that aspect to it I
I think I got to into that a little bit
more do do you I mean do you ever run
into scenarios where like you're hacking
a Target and you just find like an
absolute [__] ton of mediums and highs
that are not pre-auth rce or even
criticals that are that are not pre-auth
rce right and then those earnings from
reporting those bugs to zdi outweigh the
the the money that you make from
submitting the preo rcees so myself I
mean that's not the case for myself at
least but I do know some other folks
that are doing a lot of
and they're fighting a lot of lows and
mediums by fuzzing different file types
and protocols and and yeah uh they they
do uh a bunch of money for that that's
interesting that's really interesting
yeah I I got to I got to think about
that alrighty Richard what's on the
docking for today oh an ASMR ad say L I
got you I got you all right guys so
today we're gonna ah attack surface
management roles not as okay I got you
well if we're talking about attack
surface management then of course we're
talking about the ASD note team right
the ogs in the ASM space and this time
around they've released a new community
project their attack surface management
job board a place where you can see all
of the companies that are hiring for
attack surface management jobs so if
you're interested in that sort of thing
if you're a Recon heavy hacker or if you
just want to get your hands on the aset
no product to play around with it um
then definitely check out that job board
that's going to be at asset
note. asset note. ASMR I'm going to make
them change to ASMR so if you want to
support the Pod or if you want to check
out that job board head over to asset
note. ASMR all right back to the show
let's
go um okay we spent a good amount of
time on the uh on on the the live
hacking event flow and that whole thing
now so let's jump a little bit more into
your methodology okay um so obviously
you know you've got this you've got this
iot uh IC hacking side and you've got
this you know web hacking side um
how do you the one I'm more interested
in picking your brain on is this iot
hacking side so what is the overall
methodology when you get a new device um
how important is you know getting
firmware getting a dynamic debugger that
sort of thing and what what is your
approach yeah cool so whenever you
research iot or uh OT devices you know
controllers uh and and stuff like that
uh the most important thing is obviously
to get the fare um and getting the FW um
there are multiple ways to get the where
if it's super easy sometimes you can
download it from the vendor website uh
you know because they offer it to to
their customers uh in most cases it's
not uh it's not uh plain Tech so it's
encrypted uh and then you have like
different methodologies of how to to to
handle that sometimes the vendor offers
to download uh previous versions of the
frameware to and then you go one by one
until you find uh unencrypted one
decrypted one uh and inside the
transition firmware will contain also
the the algorithm and the key for the
encrypted one dude that is a good that
is a good tip right there so at some
point if they switch from non-encrypted
to encrypted go back to the last version
wow because somehow the the corent
firware needs to understand how to
install the encrypted one how to decrypt
and install the the new frameware right
so we go one by one until we found this
transition frameware and then uh we we
uh develop the the decryption process
ourselves wow um sometimes sometimes if
you are able to exploit a current device
uh and uh research its binaries and then
you can uh get root access to the device
and then uh explore and research the the
binaries and you'll find the decryption
uh procedure in these binaries so we can
take it to decrypt the the filers uh and
sometimes if uh you're you have no Lu
you need to Des Soldier the The Flash
chip and read the frameware out of the
device itself um dude yeah that's so
much it's so much work to do that right
that's one of the things with iot
devices that hurts me a little bit as a
web Hunter because like as a web Hunter
I can go focus on some of these high
dollar you know web paying programs and
pop some bugs that are going to pay
really great bounties or I can spend a
week you know like but think about it
think about it like this what what what
if you could spend a lot of time to get
the source code of the server that
you're trying to it would be so worth it
it would be so worth it exactly exactly
so if you get if you get a FW uh you
it's not a black box anymore it becomes
a gray box so uh obviously if you want
to be successful with uh embedded
devices you need to get the FW and and
usually these are the three methods like
download from the from the ventor
website find the transition between the
encrypt and encrypted hack the device
Itself by finding kind um uh post of
remote code executions blackbox wise
sometimes it's possible uh and then get
the binaries extract the the decryption
process and implement it or desolder the
flash chip and read the funware out of
the device so once you have the firware
you're you're in in a great position to
start uh researching uh the the platform
itself so so you've got the firmware you
know do you normally work on a live
device or do you try to get that
firmware emulated so it's it's a great
question um we uh we usually start from
emulation
because sometimes the the device uh you
cannot buy the device it's expensive it
will take a lot of time uh uh to reach
us so we're starting from emulation
because it helps us to to to get
ourselves familiar with the environment
like uh what do we need to patch in
order to make it work uh what are the
main binaries how the operating system
and the file system uh is is arranged so
it gives us a lot of it's a lot of hard
work Hands-On hard hard work but it's
worth it because after emulating the
device we in most cases understand
really good the uh the environment and
how it works like from the inside yeah
uh but but yeah in many cases we also uh
uh purchase the
device uh and uh we work on a on a real
device yeah dude that's that's super
badass man you know like I I would love
to have a an emulated environment for
the some of these iot devices that I've
hacked on because it's such a pain when
you like mess something up and you're
going all right I got to unplug it and
plug it back in and afid to reboot and
if I could just go you know just rewind
it so we create Ducker files and then
you can just rebooted so so the most
experience that I've had with this is
like taking a binary put it in in qemu
and like do a little bit of work on it
because of the the situation that we
were in um so what does it look like to
pull the firmware off of a device and
and have all these different partitions
and you've got just like your IMG file
or whatever right this like raw DD that
you pulled off the device um and then
get that into an an emulator and emulate
all these different partitions and align
everything so that the the thing
actually starts up when you boot it yeah
so not necessarily you'll need all the
file system uh so sometimes you want
only uh a specific binary that
responsible for the main logic let's
take example
um um iot device let's say a camera most
of the camera's logic will be
implemented in one binary and you don't
need all the partitions and everything
you just need this one binary to work so
but doesn't it crash all the time if you
don't have like maybe I'd imagine that's
the case but maybe that's not the case
so so you start you know you start from
okay just the binary itself and then it
doesn't work why because it's looking
for these and that libraries okay so you
take all the you extract all the
libraries and you place it in the right
place and then uh you iterate through
this process until the binary works and
you just work with one binary and all
the peripherials so you don't need all
the file system in most cases right yeah
dude that's I I guess that's one of
those things that you just like I
wouldn't have tried because I would have
assumed it's too it's too like pece meal
where it's like ah I got to get this
piece and then you know then I hit like
this subp part of the application and it
freaks out because I missing this folder
and you know yeah obviously sometimes
you need to patch the binary itself you
know because uh let's say it's looking
for a very specific component Hardware
component that you don't have because
it's simulation and it's not it's not
implemented it in qmu so you patch this
uh this part to to just work like return
zero or something if it's not important
for the device itself yeah wow you
really have to get in the weeds with
that binary then and understand exactly
what's happen you have to you you have
to really understand what it's doing and
you have to reverse and generate uh
really good to understand what it's
supposed to do why for for example let's
talk about the patient monitor for
example so for the the main logic of the
entire patient monitor uh at least in
the case that I researched it was
implemented one binary but this binary
had a lot of uh communication you know
serial communication uh to peripherals
of the patient monitor the spo2 like the
the O2 um levels of your blood so I we
just patched all these functions and and
the device thought yeah here is the o to
read it's like 98% all the time right it
doesn't really matter super consistent
like always at 9 so so by bannery
punching uh you can actually skip a lot
of the the checks and all a lot of the
hurdles that a real device um uh like
simulating a real device yeah wow and
and when you're when you're going about
that how are you how are you doing these
binary patches uh so usually you work
with Ida or gidra so you just look at
the functions and you see uh it's
trading from from a Serial bus usually
it's from uh a specific uh device or for
example from RS uh
245 uh or whatever and you just patch
this this type of um functionality and
does does g and and Ida have
functionality built into the
applications to do that or are you just
opening up in a hex Setter and then
modifying it afterwards uh doesn't
really matter I usually use a hack
editor but I mean yeah both g r and
uh have this functionality binary P I'm
I'm just old school I'm using hex yeah
that's the only thing I've done in with
binary patching just very limited hex
editor Let Me modify this like string or
tweak this one little little flow it
sounds to be honest it sounds
intimidating but but in reality it's
very simple you just skip a function you
just nope a function and that's it yeah
yeah no that that makes sense it is
intimidating but it is it is doable and
and I have to say like the the scenario
in which I did it was um there was this
binary that was being loaded up by a
mobile app that I needed to modify a
little piece of and I was like racking
my head I was like man I can't get this
to work with Freda you know like like
why can't I hook it oh it's in the
native binary a this is such a pain and
then my buddy was like man you should
just like patch the the binary you know
the doo file and I was like yeah you
know dude that sounds really painful and
like 15 minutes later it was done you
know it's it's not it's not that bad if
you know exactly where you need to
modify um exactly so that's that's that
is pretty rad that that is something you
just got to take the Deep dive on and
and do it I think um definitely
definitely and again emulating devices I
think it's worth the time again we're
not emulating the entire device and not
the inter uh peripheral just the the
logic itself that we're focused on
that's a great that's a great piece of
advice I think that's something that
I'll try next time around is is you know
when I get the firmware off I'll try to
put it into maybe I'll allocate a day to
it or something like that of trying to
get that you know identify the main
binary the main functionality and then
just get all of the peripherals that it
needs
um I know this probably varies from from
um from you know project to project from
Target to Target but um how long does it
take typically for you to let's say you
pulled
firmware how long does it take for you
to get it spun up in in qmu or whatever
so it really depends how complex the
device is so for example the patient
monitor that I I talked about it had a
lot of peripheral so we needed to patch
it one by one and understand how it
works one by one so it took some time it
took a couple of days but sometimes
especially if we're talking about
routers uh that qmu has some initial
support for for a lot of them uh it's
really easy you can you can get a fer
and uh and start working with K in a
couple of hours wow dude yeah that that
that's a good a good piece for the the
hacker one you know people listening is
like you know a lot of times if we're in
the competitions we don't have a lot of
time and we're like ah is this worth my
time to actually get an emulation
environment set up but if you can get it
set up in a couple hours totally worth
it you know for sure and then you got
Dynamic debugging and it's like ah it's
beautiful um yeah exactly and then you
can reboot it any time you can change it
you can modify it you can uh you can
patch some functionality that you're not
interested in uh you can bypass
anti-debugging techniques yeah yeah set
up some fuzzing easy H it's great um
Okay cool so that's a that's those are
some awesome takeaways my favorite ones
from that was the the find the the
unencrypted version to the encrypted
version transition yeah transition
version yeah I love that that is great
man okay let's talk about um I guess the
one of the main areas that you focus on
and uh which is the iot communications
with the mothership you know with the
cloud so to speak um that's something
that we also had another researcher Matt
Brown come on and talk about uh recently
and and so when I whenever I hear you
know two hackers that I respect talk
about the same thing at the same time
I'm like look this is something we need
to really deep dive and understand
thoroughly um so so what does that what
does that process look like how are you
normally going about it setting up you
know middleman for those Communications
and what kind of protocols and patterns
do you see yeah so you know whenever we
we're researching a device you modin
device okay we're talking about modin
devices uh they're not uh Standalone
they usually communicate with some kind
of a cloud I I call this a cloud like a
main server Mothership whatever you want
to call it um and they exchange data uh
what kind of data they exchange for
example um normally modern devices will
be managed by uh
user account so you have your account
you can log in from your mobile
application and then through the cloud
to device uh you can control it and we
are very interested in in this type of
communication because uh if we could uh
do a count takeover or device takeover
uh the terminology is not invented yet I
guess yeah these these are new Vol
classes really in this scenario yeah
yeah so so instead of controlling your
device you're actually controlling
another device and then you can interact
with it through the cloud so you don't
have to be in the same network local era
network with this device and you can
actually buy us firewalls and not uh
segregation and control remoted devices
so that's a very powerful end of the
world man that is like the the Holy
Grail of like and I think in one of your
your I think it was one of your Defcon
talks you guys talked about a scenario
with a couple devices actually where
you're able to like emulate you know
impersonate the device to the cloud push
a config up and then pull yourself out
so it pushes that config back down to
the actual device and it's like oh my
gosh this is so bad so so I think in in
many cases the device to Cloud
communication is overlooked by
developers because they focus on the
user to Cloud functionality and they do
a lot of checks over there so are you uh
asking the the right device uh you know
roll permissions and uh account
permissions and uh 32 uh character long
password
will not protect you but the device
itself the functionality that is loaded
into the device that communicates to the
CL in many cases uh unfortunately this
is overlooked uh because developers are
not considering this as they don't to
see attack Vector yeah because they they
kind of say to their themselves I guess
okay what happens if someone uh imp
person a device nothing right but that
that's not the reality because if you
can impersonate a device and you can
actually tell the cloud uh uh to change
configuration about yourself as a device
in many cases this could lead to a
device takeover that you can actually
add this device to your attacker's
account and then take over uh devices
that did not belong to you yeah dude
that's that's that's awesome and and so
I'm wondering what does that what does
that flow look like for you like you
know how do you how do you get the men
in the middle set up in place like I
think Matt Brown has like some script he
runs like um uh mum router or something
like that or some people use like Wi-Fi
pineapple what are you using for that uh
so again it depends the project but
usually what I do is I have my own kind
of router that I can fully control and I
place it uh uh before the device itself
and then since I'm I'm the router I
control the DHCP I control the DNS I
control the traffic um and uh what I
usually do is I do https uh downgrade
attack so usually I'm converting
everything into http and again you can
do it by multiple ways for example you
can inject uh your ca into the device uh
you can um if there is a uh cert pin
inside the the logic you can patch it to
accept your certificate your ca um and
basically what what I try to do is uh I
try to make sure that the communication
is HTP and htps and then it's really
easy uh to do a man in the middle and
intervene in the communication so if
you're doing a I'm not super familiar
with the flow for a downgrade attack are
you doing something you know patching
something at the the binary level just
make it HTP rather than htps or you
actually like getting a an htps server
that it trusts you know and your man in
the middle that with a trusted
certificate and then you know
redirecting to to htgp so we can we can
we can double down that so there there
are multiple scenarios uh the first
scenario is there is hardcoded um um
sorry not there is a configuration for
the the main binary that needs to
communicate with the server right and
you simply change in the configuration
you change the address from
htps Cloud to http cloud and you're
done um and in other scenarios this is
not a configuration this is actually
being downloaded from uh from the cloud
as configuration so you find a way to
intervene maybe in the memory Maybe you
doing some binary patching uh and change
from htps to http wow okay okay that's
fine and in other scenarios you can
actually use htps and you just add your
ca uh to The Trusted CA store inside the
device oh yeah of course if you got it
emulated you can just do that super easy
and then you use the DNS server that you
own to actually give the device whenever
it request to resolve uh the Ser the
server you give it your own address and
then uh since you are the server for the
device right now and you they trust your
ca then you can actually do SSL
termination and then the device
communicates to your Cloud which is not
a real cloud with htps and then you do
SSL termination and you actually from
your device your server you communicate
to the real cloud and then you kind of
do a real man in the middle wow cool and
what kind of tools are you using for
that SSL termination and that whole
impersonation process uh so so usually
we have kind of uh Python scripts to do
most of that uh custom custom stuff uh
but again you have you have like ready
made tools like in the middle SSL is
really great um uh but but again it
really depends the the project and uh
how uh how things are set up yeah
exactly how things are set up very cool
man okay so you you're you're you're men
in the middle in that communication um
what kind of Protocols are you seeing
for that communication is it typically
just hitting an htttp API or what
uh again we're talking about a broad uh
variety of of devices but but in most
cases yeah most cases uh um it's htps
and and in some cases you also have some
uh proprietor protocols that uh that are
specific to some
devices um but yeah in most cases it
would be htps and all the device to
Cloud communication will go over the
htps you know to transfer configuration
to update to do kind of a keep alive to
update the strew to do uh over thear
updates um so most of the communication
will be over htps gotcha that makes
sense um yeah dude it it sounds like so
much fun man I think my favorite hacking
experience overall was was hacking an
iot device like I've just had so much
fun with that so I I think for me it's a
little bit hard to to focus on hacking
those devices with the opportunity cost
of web you know and and it being such my
you know bread and butter something that
I I can do pretty easily um but man it's
so fun when you yeah obviously it's
different it's a different
speciality one thing that is interesting
to say that uh p in Pon toon in the iot
theme competition they have this cool uh
smashup um uh kind of a feature you can
call it where they offer you 100K if you
are able to exploit from the one into a
router and from the router exploit a a
local device iot device like a camera
wow so if you're able to provide uh uh
to show demonstrate a full exploit that
you hack a router from the outside from
the one and from inside uh do what you
want to do and then hack and uh exploit
a device uh iot device from the inside
and again they have like a very specific
Target list for each Lan and one
categories uh they they offer this uh
they offer 100K wow dude that's that's a
pretty insane setup there if you could
literally just go from W to to Shell on
an internal device that's exactly and
and they do this because they want uh
they want like the real experience they
want the real thing uh and and it's
great uh we've been doing this um uh a
couple of times I know that other others
anology did it also how often do people
pull it
off um uh they started like I think year
ago
so um
maybe maybe five or 10ish so far my gosh
dude that's crazy I I went to a local
talk in in Richmond we we have a a
conference here in Richmond Virginia um
called rvac and one of the guys uh I
think one of the tenable researchers
who's actually done some Pondo and stuff
I think was giving a presentation on
like poning all these routers that he he
does for his work stuff and one of the
things he was saying was that um the wi
interfaces on these are a little bit
whack sometimes because uh over over
ipv4 you know you've got your Fireball I
know I know this guy he did the IPv6
exploited dude I remember my mind was
blown when he presented that yeah it's
it's this is one of the things that is
usually overlooked by uh kind of a low
tier router vendors that that are not
Enterprise right the IPv6 one uh because
they there is a different IP table for
ipv4 and IPv6
and usually whenever you configure the
router uh to block or to do something
with uh uh the IP table usually
developers will go to the ipv4 and they
forget to configure the IPv6 and and
that's why uh sometimes you can
communicate with routers from the one
using IPv6 even though it's it's need to
be blocked it's terrifying that is
absolutely terrifying man that that you
might be exposing services on your on
your Wan side via IPv6 exactly think
about kind of uh local only services
that are supposed to be uh communicated
only from the the local area network are
Exposed on the one yeah that's great
terrifying terrifying okay so so let's
go back to that um you know man in the
middle and and I know you know we were
shooting for an hour are we we're going
a little long here is that okay with you
yeah yeah I'm with you dude I I'm into
it man I'm still I'm still I'm still
getting a ton out of this so talk to me
a little bit about how it works for you
to impersonate devices to the cloud what
is your approach there you know
obviously you get them in and the middle
in place what kind of Trends do you see
uh that that people make mistakes on
when securing that cloud to device
communication okay so the thing about uh
imprisoning devices is uh to collect
enough information uh about the device
that uh will gain us the ability to
impersonate it in front of the cloud now
think about it this way so there is a
vendor that manufactures a lot of
devices right and they need to keep
track of these devic
uh on how uh uh whenever they leave the
factory on how the devices can
communicate with the mothership with the
cloud uh so they have these unique
identifiers that tells the cloud yeah
device presents to the cloud this unique
identifier you can call it a token you
can call it a cereal you can call it
combination of cereal and me something
that the the cloud will be able to
verify that yes this is a real authentic
device that left our Factory and in some
cases these identifiers are not unique
enough and are not um strong enough so
in some cases you can brute force them
you can um um you can guess them uh uh
or you can uh come up with uh your
identifiers that the cloud will trust
you to be an authentic device now the
thing is what if you're able to get
identifiers of another device that not
does not belong to you like your device
is ABC and you're able to get a device
that is identifi XY Z then you can take
these identifiers you can even plug it
into your device and then communicate to
the cloud and the cloud would think oh
okay this device is not ABC this is XY Z
oh my gosh and it has this scenario that
I'm describing it has some implications
on how the cloud is communicating to the
device because right now the user of the
device that owns XY Z will communicate
to your
device because the cloud think that XYZ
is this device that just a moment before
was ABC and and this cross interactions
between different devices and different
users uh we found multiple ways to abuse
this into device cross account takeover
um so I can I can give you a of examples
yeah uh so for example we let's say
the the device is identify in front of
the cloud using a Serial and Mac this is
this is very common uh now the problem
with the serial in Mac is Mac is very
easy to to Brute Force because the three
first bites are the vendor oi uh and
then you have left only three bytes to
brute force or to gas and you also have
a lot of for example you go on eBay uh
you'll see a lot of pictures of devices
and you'll see the mech address uh and
the seral on top of the device oh no
that's bad yeah so so let's let's say
you went on eBay you saw a make address
in a cereal or you you saw some YouTube
videos of uh uh folks uh doing kind of
uh uh unboxing unboxing or something I
love that attack Vector that's great
exactly and you get and you get the the
mech and cereal so you take this Mech
and cereal and and it is being used like
like credentials to the cloud and then
you connect to the cloud the cloud
thinks that you
are device XY Z and what you can do with
that is in some cases you can as the
device you can tell the cloud um I
belong to this user right so what you do
is you take the the credential the
cereal and make of some device and then
you tell it yeah I actually belong to
the attacker's account and then suddenly
in the attack account they get a new
device oh my gosh so this scenario uh it
it sounds ridiculous but uh
unfortunately it's very common in iot uh
to do kind of a account takeover yeah so
device takeover de device takeover and
then and then correlate it with the
account that's with the attacker account
that's a that's a good flow and I'm
wondering whether you
think
the correlation of these of these
devices you know to to your account and
and
like being able to do that from
something that is on the outside of the
box or on the outside of the router like
is that always insecure because of this
unboxing scenario because that's a great
point I mean these are influencers too
right you know like like these are these
are high value targets for attackers and
if they're if they're showing if they're
flipping the device over and that sort
of thing and that in sort of information
can be leaked just from an external
perspective of the device that's a
problem I think right it is it is a
problem and and again not all the
devices are insecure in that manner but
um the modern devices like the protected
or secure devices use strong identifiers
that cannot it's impossible to brute
force or to guess or to view from the
outside uh because they will use some
kind of uh internal in most cases
Hardware based um uh identifier that
cannot be guessed and cannot be used uh
like a private key uh that is embedded
inside the device itself in in a special
storage uh that cannot be easily
accessed Ian and even if it could be
accessed you'll need a lot of effort and
physical access to the device um in
order to to get it and usually it will
be burned uh through uh in through into
the device through the factory man
manufacturing process and like some some
sort of um you know secure Enclave or
like what what are the other other ways
that they store this information exactly
secure Enclave usually mod uh mod
approach is OTP fuses so uh it's like
onetime programing fuse memory that is
uh uh one time programing like written
once and that's it you cannot uh write
to it anymore and only the device the
internal uh architecture of the device
uh can use this information as the
identifier or kind of an internal
configuration that identifies this
device only wow dude so actually device
becomes instead of just logically just a
Serial and Mac it actually becomes part
of the device itself like Hardware wise
yeah so the P you need the PCB with the
components soldered to it in order to
impersonate the device so that makes
sense and I've got one more question
here before we switch over to some of
your your other you know bug Bounty
related stuff um the this the randomness
that's required to secure these devices
right um you know say you've got a a
string you know maybe it's got like 900
million possibilities or whatever right
like that that that I mean if you've got
a you know a million devices right in
and and you've got all the time in the
world that's still not not secure enough
right you need to have something that is
massively random especially if you've
got a ton of devices in order so I mean
if you see a hex string and it's just a
hex string and it's not you know 20
characters long then it's it's it's a
problem it is and and that's why modern
devices will use a private key uh you
know 20 48 a bit L at least uh that's
impossible to imperson yeah wow that for
for for my like bug Bounty brain that's
a little bit a little bit tricky because
a lot of the times you know for us we're
talking about things that can be
enumerated pretty quickly or are used
for an explain in that regard but when
there's so many devices across the whole
the whole flow that's uh that's
different as well okay so let 24 bit is
enough okay great I'll be on the lookout
for that um so so let's go into some of
your um let's jump over to some of your
bug Bounty stuff right now and and we
put some questions in in the dock here
and man you really delivered some
awesome questions on this one and good
and good tips in in the prep here so I'm
really excited to break these apart one
of the things you say your secret is uh
is is being able to re like replicate a
bunch of work done by others and right
you know Chiron I I don't understand how
are you doing all this binary research
and and doing bug Bounty and then also
just on the side casually reproducing
all the bugs that come through your your
pipeline here like talk talk to me about
that like yeah yes yeah first of all I'm
flatter thank you but uh first of all
I'm not I'm not young anymore I'm uh 30
30 year old uh so I have around 15 years
of uh uh experience and uh um a lot of
time uh to to try a bunch of different
approaches and uh and stuff you're still
actively replicating bugs though right
to this day yeah so what what I try to
do so I wrote kind of uh like many
others I wrote like a small bot that
will Scout the internet and find me
articles and interesting bugs According
to some uh
parameters uh and uh I tried at least
once a day to read one or two
articles uh in some topics for example a
new method for fuzzing right so uh not
not statically fuzzing uh uh but Network
wasse fuzzing and then I tried to
replicate it um and use it in my line of
work so I I take it and and I try to
think how can I use it in in our own lab
research and the way that I replicate
This research is uh kind of aligns with
the stuff that I I normally do so uh
this way I'm able to also do the work
that I need to do but also uh improve it
with innovative ways that others are
finding so wow I think I think this is a
I'm not sure if to say this is my SEC
about I try to to be very up to dat with
all the techniques all the methods all
the new research uh and and try to
implement it uh into my work you know
that's very different man than a lot of
people because a lot of people they get
to a certain point where they're having
success and then they just want to they
just like get addicted to that and
they're just like a I just want to I'm
talking about myself as well you know I
get I get addicted to finding these bugs
in bug Bounty and getting these you know
big payouts and that sort of thing and
that's all I want to do with my time is
pluck pluck pluck you know keep on
grabbing these
and and you know uh things like that and
I think but I think you'll run out of
idors eventually right because everybody
are are there's a lot of bug Bounty
programs out there shiron like yeah okay
so you know okay so if you're talking
about this so maybe you automated
somehow yeah in a large scale right so
you you still innovate and and improve
yourself because otherwise all the the
new bug Bounty um that that are doing
some kind of automations uh will eat you
yeah I I think it's it's a I think
that's true and and we're always forced
to grow as hackers and that's one of the
things that I like about my job here
running this podcast is that I'm I have
the opportunity to sit down and talk to
you about techniques you use and
research all of these techniques as
they're coming out and and delivering
that to the to the public but I think
that if you say once or twice a day
you're sitting down reading these these
uh you know writeups and trying to
replicate them as well right that's
that's a big piece you can read it not
all of them not all of them of course
but but yeah I'm trying to use new new
tools new methods um uh new ideas yeah
I'm trying to
implement all of them not all of them
right but a big portion of them in my
line of work let let this be let this be
a uh a notice to all the hackers that
are out there listening to this because
even this guy is still is still doing
all that I think we could all use a
little bit more of that um okay I I've
got a couple things here I want to talk
to you about the not so common attack
surfaces that you that you like to to go
after we we covered sort of iot devices
and that sort of thing so far um but
you've got some some cool other things
you like to go at in the in the bug
Bounty
world uh yeah
so I I have like these two hats right
I'm doing I'm doing bug bounties and I
also do uh binary exploitation and phone
to own so if if we're talking about
specifically bug bounties then I try to
look uh uh uh at the not so common
attack surface so just like you said uh
usually most modern bug bounty hunters
um I I'd like to say for some reason are
going directly to web and bu bound is
not just web but for some reason for
some reason it's it's like u u the
terminology is mixed uh and bugbounty
when when you say bount usually refer to
web but I I try to look at other attack
surfaces like uh DB to host Escape so
sometimes s will give you the the
ability to write into databases and
databases are are complex Bas so usually
databases are very complex uh um
platforms uh not not usually not like
web platforms but they're are they're
not just uh for storing data they they
contain a lot of different features and
if you have the ability uh to to control
somehow even your own database in many
cases you can can leverage this into
database to host escape and uh use some
features abuse some features of the
database to escape uh from the database
realm into the ow platform and then from
there to propagate and do maybe account
takeovers maybe uh get into other uh
databases it really depends the platform
but I'm I'm trying to do I'm trying to
do a bunch of
those that's that is definitely a an
attack surface that not a lot of um bug
bounty hunters are are going after so I
I definitely I think this also decreases
your dup ability right like you know
there's a much lower chance you're going
to get dupes when you're going after
these these really crazy attack surfaces
exactly um and I see another one that
you have here on the doc is sort of like
external scanning or attacking services
that aren't necessarily HTTP based and
right exactly that's that's a crazy one
and and just anecdotally I remember one
live hacking event with another great
hacker random deduction um she she went
after these uh UDP based protocols that
were all over the place on this on this
attack surface and you know most of the
time let's say there's there's you know
most of the hackers that are just going
after hgdp stuff and then there's a
wider you know uh percentage of hackers
that are going after okay you know I'll
take a look at some you know TCP Based
Services that are not HTTP right you
know because I'm I'm G to be thorough
here and then there's even smaller set
that actually goes after anything UDP
based and she destroyed this target uh
from some UDP based services so I bet
there is a lot of attack surface there
that we that I I and other you know
primarily web-based hackers look over a
lot yeah for sure so just like I said
almost all the bu B Hunters are hunting
web applications but in many cases you
you also find uh different protocols
like TCP or UDP that are supported by
the targets uh and since I personally
have uh a deep background into protocol
analis butter yeah yeah exactly so I I
tried uh I tried to to hunt for other
protocols other than HTTP uh some
sometimes for example uh doing stuff
with ntp and uh uh distributed in out of
service like if you can uh create these
loops with ntp or to do stuff with SNP
which which are great protocols to
manage devices and they're they're
implemented in almost any device that
you can think of the the problem is
whether they're exposed uh over the the
internet or not uh and since they're UDP
based both uh uh ntp and um SNMP uh in
many cases again not always in many
cases they're overlooked in in the
firewall rules and firewall policies and
if you'll do uh these type of scans uh
or you you'll use Showdown or tenses to
do these type of scin for you you'll
find a bunch of uh uh uh targets that
are actually uh listening for esoteric
protocols and and these oric um um
services that you can actually abuse and
and and play with wow dude that's that
sounds like a lot of fun a lot a lot of
fun in those I'm wondering have you ever
looked at like sip protocol or I'm
trying to remember what the those names
of those Protocols are that are like the
routing protocols surrounding sip uh I
can't pull them off the top of my head
but that's the majority of the
experience that I've had with non hdp
related protocol is is is sip related
stuff and I'm wondering if you find
anything there yeah so uh sip is
actually very interesting that sip is a
signaling protocol so sip itself uh sip
because there is also CIP which is a
different protocol but sip uh the
signaling Internet Protocol uh actually
is the protocol that allows you to do
the vo communication so if I want to
call to you over the internet I'm I'm
most likely using uh uh a prod suit that
starts with SIP and sip is a signaling
so I want to call you so I basically
ring or tell the server hey I want to
call
Justin and uh the server rings to you
and you get this UDP Pockets CP UDP
buckets that tells you that Chiron wants
to communicate with you and then you do
kind of a handshake and we communicate
and the interesting thing uh with the
Sip is that after you establish
communication in many cases uh we
transfer the information to communicate
directly yeah that's the interesting
part man that's what I think would be
really fun to play with yeah exactly so
we actually move from uh communicating
over the cloud to direct communication
and the the implementation for this the
the reason the logic is because we want
to communicate directly without any
interference so we don't need the server
anymore once we agree on ports to
communicate and once we agree on ports
to communicate we start to uh transfer
media and media is voice and video in
most cases so there are a bunch of
different protocols so you have sdp to
actually communicate what type of ports
and what type of media so for example
I'm telling you yeah I'm going to
transfer to you audio in this and that
format AAC and whatever and and you have
another protocol for transfer the RTP to
transfer the actual media itself so it's
a bunch of protocols that eventually
allows us to communicate over VoIP and
there is a lot of attack service over
there the problem is most of the modin
applications so for let's say WhatApp or
telegram right they're using protocol
Stacks uh modern protocol Stacks that
have been scrutinized and looked and
reviewed a lot of time uh in in in
different directions so it's very
difficult to find uh bugs in those areas
the potential for bugs in those areas is
only if you uh take a look at the glue
between the library itself the protocol
stack itself and the application maybe
you'll find uh a bug over there wow dude
dude I just want to I just want to tell
the guests I did not this was not in the
dock at all like I we didn't mention
anything about sip beforehand so that
that whole explanation about how sip
protocol Works was just off the top of
his head which is just no it's because I
researched uh I researched a couple of
uh uh um uh SE protocol Stacks um and I
actually found a bug uh or vulnerability
actually I I so I can call you and uh
crush your application remotely over
over the the server yeah uh in one of
the popular uh sip stocks so that's why
I know about sip specifically that's fun
man yeah I I when I found some bugs in
the Sip Sip stuff A lot of it was having
to do with the um extra layer of
authentication on top of sip um and and
so there we we got to a point where we
were able to impersonate people and do
like third party registration which is a
part of the protocol um which was really
which was really fun um cool yeah all
right let me let me I'll let you go soon
Shan I I I got this I just want to talk
really quickly about the documentation
tracker and the uh recapture bypass
stuff that you that you put in the dock
yeah so uh when I work on uh uh let's
call it uh a long-term research uh I I
try to to be on top of things like new
features uh new updates it's uh change
logs stuff like that uh so for heavy
heavy targets I'm I'm writing in most
cases I'm writing a kind of a
documentation tracker so a documentation
tracker uh is a is a Fluff name to say
that I'm scraping the [__] out of them
yeah
exactly you know uh uh the commentation
pages and uh release note pages and
product pages and uh um updates and
GitHub repositories so I get all of this
data and then I try to to write what I
call some modules so for example uh I
have a module that uh uh summarize
everything into what uh what new uh
versions are available uh what is what
is the difference between uh different
versions of an application uh sometimes
you know for a very specific and focused
uh um targets I I also do kind of
automatic installation and the binary
diffing and again this is all part of
the automation uh but again the the the
essence of it is to to understand and be
on top of things like what are the new
apis what are the new versions features
Etc yeah that's massive man I think I
think a lot of people uh you know think
about automation as like all right let
me do scanning let me see new assets
that are popping up sort of an ASM sort
of scenario but in my experience doing
do doation tracking Andor um JS file
diffing if you're looking at a specific
um you know web application over time
man you get so much cool stuff out of
that and you you're the first one to
touch it too because it just got pushed
um exactly and that's the key that's the
key when you do bug bounty on scale the
key is to be first and uh the way to do
that is to to get a notification the the
second there is a new version yeah
exactly so so how does this recapture
bypass thing work because I I I've done
a lot of documentation tracking stuff
but haven't ever integrated any
recapture bypass stuff to any of my
workflows when creating accounts or
anything yeah so um I I mean in many
cases when I do uh um mostly uh brute
force uh or uh let's say account
takeovers for different reasons
different reasons it doesn't have to be
specifically for scraping but scraping
is is a good use case for it uh you'd
want to have a lot of accounts when and
when I say a lot of accounts I'm not
talking about 10 I'm talking about like
hundreds or thousands of accounts uh and
you can in some cases do it manually
like uh uh go one by one and uh click
I'm not a robot uh but essentially you
want to automate this uh because you
want to make to make it work fast in in
scale so uh there are some services
online like two capture.com uh that
allow you to bypass some of the the
captas but not they they don't work uh
in in 100% of the cases so sometimes
they they won't work and and I found uh
this you know super stupid simple method
uh to to bypass the recapture by
automating my using GUI automating my
mouse C oh no way well I mean it's it's
it's a bit smarter it's not like XY
coordinates of the of the mouse it's
like uh hooking to components uh use
uh specific classes or ID of the div or
something like okay got in the Dom
exactly and then you move the mouse over
there and you do clicks uh and you you
can automate it there there are a lot of
different extensions to Chrome and
Firefox to do that for example uh UI
vision is one of them uh yeah I mean you
can you can just Google uh UI automation
Google Chrome extension and and you'll
find a bunch of them and surprisingly
they work I wouldn't say flawlessly but
like in in a great percentage percentage
of the time they work great and you can
just use it to open a thousand of
accounts now you need different email
accounts right uh so uh what I do is I
just use uh Gmail with the plus with
with a
plus at the end and and in most websites
not on most platforms they will consider
it as different accounts and it will
reach the same uh May block so so we
just activated it by automation through
your uh email account and you use the
automation to to click and open all the
account uh and and it just works dude
that's that's awesome man it's pretty
simple to set up I mean yeah it's it's
very simple to set up and and and it it
works great wow that's that's super cool
man yeah I haven't had to use that but I
could see that being super helpful for
for scraping or for you know hitting API
rate limits or something like that being
able to have M SCP
if you want sometime to brute force uh
you know otps to do account takeover
that's great too yeah no that's that's
perfect um here's here's the last little
little section and then I'll let you go
I'm sorry I know I said that a couple
times but you have such
interesting um solving so I I want to
move away from the bug Bounty stuff
you've given us enough tidbits for a
lifetime um and I want to talk about why
are you like what is this scan my SMS
thing and oh and like and like what what
what makes you move from protocol
engineer binary exploitation bug Bounty
and all of a sudden you know what I'm
just gonna solve fishing in Israel yeah
yeah you know so tell me about the
project for the people the best the best
way to do something is is to be scammed
like motivation right uh so the the
thing that will move you the most is if
one of your closed uh friends or family
uh got hit by a scammer uh then and you
know you have all these YouTube uh
channels that they try to pay back to
the the scammers so in Israel uh there
is this uh uh there are a there are a
lot of scams uh via SMS smishing what we
call smashing and because nobody wants
to take the responsibility uh and there
is almost no money in it because the end
user will almost never will never pay
for uh checking if something is fishing
or not uh once my wife uh got scammed I
decided uh that I want to create like a
center place for people to be able to uh
to know if the SMS they received is
legitimate or not because there are many
services in Israel organizations that
are using SMS as as a legitimate method
to provide information and they send you
this shorter shortener uh links uh with
the text and and obviously attackers and
the the bad guys try to are trying to
imitate it and they just copy paste the
text and replace it with another uh
bitly kind of uh uh shortener URL and
you have the the the citizen the the end
user I call this end user but it's
actually a citizen has no way to
understand or to know if it's a
legitimate or not so I just uh built an
automation that actually scans these
URLs actually uh keep Tru on all the r
directions and uh do some kind of
analysis on the end website like what
type of text HTML what kind of images so
for example if I'm identify uh images of
financial institutions and the the name
of the website domain is not something
that I know of so probably it's a
fishing so I have this scoring mechanism
wow that's that's pretty technically
Advanced there wow okay cool yeah so I I
really wanted to provide a tool for
citizens uh to be able to to understand
if the SMS they received is legitimate
or not and and it actually uh cut so in
Israel I wouldn't say everybody but a
lot of people are using this and they're
actually using this uh service free
service uh for the public uh to
understand if the SMS they received is
is legitimate or not wow dude the uh the
Israeli government should should buy
this from you and and host it on like a
on like Government website and because
it's massive problem and it's something
that affects the the whole citizen base
like you said um and wow dude and so I
guess do this is using uh like AI to to
check it out or is it actually hardcode
all of it that reaches out to the back
end and like runs through an analysis
based off of like the HTML and stuff
like that yeah so so we have a couple of
different modules uh I can I can talk
about a few of them so for example we
have yeah we have ai that goes over the
text to understand if it's legitimate
text or not but again since uh bad guys
are copying and pasting the same text in
many cases uh it's difficult for the AI
to catch on it because it's it's a
legitimate text just bad link right so
most of the automation is focused on um
the scanning of the link itself like
unfolding unfolding I think this is the
right terminology uning the the link and
and keep track of all the redirections
and then check for each Direction all
the certificates uh all the authenticity
of the website we're checking the third
party providers like if it's a in a bad
uh Blacklist kind of uh thing and then
for the final website we're checking all
the URLs in the final website uh for
example scammers really like to send the
so they hate writing their own uh server
back end so they just use telegram API
to send the the fishing data to the
telegram API so in many cases in many
cases you you'll find fishing kits that
they have no backend it's just whenever
you fill all the details and click
submit right like here is my bank
account is the password y y y and click
submit it will all this information will
be sent to a telegram bot without any uh
um backend service so we're looking at
all these kind of uh uh um uh indicators
as we call them and we try to reach to a
conclusion if it's fishing if it's a
scam or if it's a legitimate website wow
dude wow because I think it would have
been so easy for you to say oh we've got
this new shiny toy AI you know that that
can detect the misspellings or you know
but but if we did that we we' go we'll
be part of the problem because the
citizens do not know if the SMS they
receive is legitimate or not because
there are no tools to to actually tell
them yeah this is fully trusted or no
this is fully scam and we wanted we
wanted this binary uh result true or
false scam or not scam uh so we had to
be a little bit more deterministic wow
dude yeah that's that's amazing I I it's
very cool to see you not get distracted
by the shiny thing that is AI and also
you know use a hard tech solution as
well in in conjunction with the AI to to
give you you know a higher signal
Boolean true or false scam or not scam
and
and and it all starts with you know a
single event that triggers everything
like my wife got scammed and I was
pissed that that's the rage the rage
built up within you yeah just like just
like when I was 16 I got the iPhone and
this was the event that that changed the
course of what interests me and I wanted
to learn more to write applications so
there is a single event that motivates
you and then you just follow this path
wow uh very cool man very cool all right
I I will I will let you go that was an
amazing episode thanks for all of the
all dets yeah it's been great having you
on man all right
peace and that's a wrap on this episode
of critical thinking thanks so much for
listening and if you want more critical
thinking content head over to ctbb show/
Discord join the Discord there's lots of
great conversations and chats going on
over there and if you want to support
the show there's the Discord subscriber
tiers which give you access to master
classes amas hack along alongs exclusive
scripts and an exclusive chat Channel
with us
we'll see you there
[Music]